♪Looking in the mirror,
my temples have turned white♪
♪Taking off the hairpins and makeup,
shedding the disguise♪
♪A cold face♪
♪With two lines of tears♪
♪If an actor could gain pity♪
♪The audience offers sincere words♪
♪Perhaps the story could be changed♪
♪The storyteller says♪
♪This mortal world is full of turmoil♪
♪Within sight but beyond reach♪
♪Yet I still don't want to give up♪
♪Don't let the memory be hollowed out♪
♪Don't make me ridiculous♪
♪Some vows turn into smoke
and fade away♪
♪Even the leaves know when autumn comes,
but you don't even know me♪
♪Imprisoned in plight,
yet still full of passion♪
♪I mock this absurd and entangled love♪
♪How can I bear to let go♪
=Whispers of Southern Song=
=Episode 12=
President Liu,
this one should finally
satisfy you, right?
Come with me to Nanyang.
I guarantee I'll make you the celebrity.
The truth that was covered up
eight years ago...
(Entertainment Tycoon Jiang Xiaoren's
New Venture: Lidu Theater)
Will finally come to light.
(Archives Room)
I have nothing to do
with that Song Xiangxiang.
You know?
It's Song Mianxiang.
Forget about whatever Xiang she is.
Well,
don't tell Chun'er.
Do you hear me?
(The Serial Murder Case in Fengcheng)
Found it.
The serial murder case
in Fengcheng eight years ago.
The killer lured women,
assaulted, and brutally murdered them.
And all nineteen deceased women
wore theatrical makeup.
The investigation showed the killer
was from an opera troupe in Fengcheng,
named Zhao Shengge.
(Zhao Shengge?)
(I've heard that name somewhere.)
Mother!
Let go!
- Mother!
- Without this rice, we'll both die.
This rice isn't even worth a bullet.
Let's go.
The next house.
(Zhang Lanying, Xu You'an's Mother)
Mother.
Don't cry.
You're Shitou. You have to be tough.
Even if you cry,
don't let them see you do it.
Alright.
I'll find a good job.
I'll earn money soon and buy you candy.
We won't have to starve anymore.
The killer Zhao Shengge was captured
and executed?
What's wrong?
Mother.
Mother,
what happened exactly?
I don't want candy anymore.
Please come back.
What are you doing?
Stop!
Brat, don't run!
Here.
Are you alright?
The one in the photo is your...
It's my mother.
I've always wanted a photo of her.
So I could look at it often
and remember her face.
So that she wouldn't remain a blur
even in my dreams.
Now I finally have a photo of her,
but it's the one the coroner took.
I don't even dare to look at it.
Back then, my mother said
she had found a good job,
and she would earn money
and buy me candy.
I waited for her candy,
but instead I got news of her death.
How could I be so stupid?
I never even thought
that she was murdered by someone.
Don't blame yourself
for what happened back then.
It wasn't your fault.
What's hateful
is that the killer is already dead.
I can't tear him to pieces.
President Jiang's death has brought up
this old case from eight years ago.
This is no coincidence.
Whether it's for Chun'er or for you,
right now we have to
get to the bottom of all this.
Get some rest.
I'll be going now.
Zhao Shengge was my master?
My master had kept a beard for years
and no longer performed.
Was it to hide the identity?
My master could never
be the serial killer.
There must be more to this.
(Rongqing Troupe)
This is the photo from the illusion.
(The one in the kingfisher phoenix crown
beside Master was Miss Jiang's mother.)
(To know the truth
about President Jiang's death,)
(come to Governor Mansion's back gate.)
♪As if it were fate♪
♪Deliberately playing tricks♪
♪We miss each other♪
♪Creating a turbulent drama♪
♪And a bizarre♪
♪Anonymous legend♪
♪The plot twists and turns♪
♪Play out over and over again♪
♪Waiting to be discarded♪
♪And you are like a moth to the flame♪
♪Refuse to submit♪
♪I can't bear to blame you♪
♪There are always too many♪
♪Helpless situations♪
♪Overwhelmed by time♪
♪Even if I have questions♪
♪I harbor desires♪
♪Nowhere to find answers♪
♪People come and go♪
♪I'm still all alone♪
♪Wandering around♪
♪Fortunate to have you with me♪
♪Go through the entanglement♪
♪If longing♪
♪Turns into dust and smoke♪
♪How can I be at ease♪
♪Having walked through prosperous times♪
♪And travelled around the world♪
♪Scars all over me♪
♪If longing never fades♪
♪Burns still hot♪
♪Let it turn into dust and smoke♪
♪After half a lifetime of loneliness♪
♪In the next life♪
♪Entangle with you again♪